const dataGk = [
    {
        question: "Nepal is geographically situated at _____ zone of of the world map.",
        optionA: "north south",
        optionB: "north east",
        optionC: "north west",
        optionD: "south west",
        correct: "b"
    },
    {
        question: "Nepal is situated in which latitude and longitude?",
        optionA: "Northern latitude and eastern latitude",
        optionB: "eastern longitude and northern longitude",
        optionC: "Northern latitude and eastern longitude",
        optionD: "Southern longitude and eastern latitude",
        correct: "c"
    },
    {
        question: "Which of the following point is correct regarding geographical coordinate of Nepal?",
        optionA: "26°22' northern latitude to 30°27' eastern latitude",
        optionB: "80°04' eastern latitude to 88°12' eastern latitude",
        optionC: "26°22' northern latitude to 30°27' northern longitude",
        optionD: "80°04' eastern longitude to 88°12' eastern longitude",
        correct: "d"
    },
    {
        question: "Which of the following point is correct regarding geographical coordinate of Nepal?",
        optionA: "26°22' northern latitude to 30°27' northern latitude",
        optionB: "80°04' eastern latitude to 88°12' eastern latitude",
        optionC: "26°22' northern longitude to 30°27' northern longitude",
        optionD: "80°04' northern longitude to 88°12' northern longitude",
        correct: "a"
    },
    {
        question: "Which is the northern most point of Nepal",
        optionA: "Changla Pass",
        optionB: "Lodabari",
        optionC: "Lelep",
        optionD: "Dodhara",
        correct: "a"
    },
    {
        question: "What is the newly revised height of Mt. Everest in m?",
        optionA: "8848.68",
        optionB: "8848.78",
        optionC: "8848.88",
        optionD: "8848.86",
        correct: "d"
    },
    {
        question: "When was the new height of Mt. Everest declared jointly by Nepal and China?",
        optionA: "2076 Kartik 23",
        optionB: "2076 Mangsir 23",
        optionC: "2077 Kartik 23",
        optionD: "2077 Mangsir 23",
        correct: "d"
    },
    {
        question: "Which is the district headquarter of Nepal at lowest and highest altitude?",
        optionA: "Jaleshwor and Jomsom",
        optionB: "Jaleshwor and Humla",
        optionC: "Biratnagar and Simikot",
        optionD: "Jaleshwor and Simikot",
        correct: "d"
    },
    {
        question: "What is the average width of Nepal?",
        optionA: "241 km",
        optionB: "193 km",
        optionC: "145 km",
        optionD: "885 km",
        correct: "b"
    },
    {
        question: "What is the geographical area of Nepal?",
        optionA: "56,728 sq. miles",
        optionB: "56,827 sq. miles",
        optionC: "56,278 sq. miles",
        optionD: "56,516 sq. miles",
        correct: "b"
    },
    {
        question: "What is the newly added area of Nepal after the addition of Limpiyadhura, Lipulekh and Kalapani in new political map of Nepal?",
        optionA: "335 sq. km",
        optionB: "355 sq. km",
        optionC: "435 sq. km",
        optionD: "455 sq. km",
        correct: "a"
    },
    {
        question: "Nepal occupies ..... percentage of total area of Nepal.",
        optionA: "0.03%",
        optionB: "0.3%",
        optionC: "0.1%",
        optionD: "0.01%",
        correct: "a"
    },
    {
        question: "When was Nepal declared as state of seven federal  provinces?",
        optionA: "2071/06/03",
        optionB: "2072/06/03",
        optionC: "2073/06/03",
        optionD: "2073/06/06",
        correct: "b"
    },
    {
        question: "Where does Gaurishankar peak lie?",
        optionA: "Ramechhap",
        optionB: "Solukhumbu",
        optionC: "Dolakha",
        optionD: "Sindhupalchowk",
        correct: "c"
    },
    {
        question: "Which district of Nepal shares its border with most number of other districts borders?",
        optionA: "Sindhuli",
        optionB: "Nawalparasi east",
        optionC: "Dolpa",
        optionD: "Chitwan",
        correct: "a"
    },
    {
        question: "Which of the following is the youngest district of Nepal?",
        optionA: "Rukum west",
        optionB: "Rukum east",
        optionC: "Nawalparasi west",
        optionD: "Nawalparasi east",
        correct: "b"
    },
    {
        question: "Which peak of Nepal is known as ladies peak?",
        optionA: "Sarje Himal",
        optionB: "Amodablem",
        optionC: "Pumori",
        optionD: "Makalu",
        correct: "b"
    },
    {
        question: "Which peak of Nepal is known as everest daughter?",
        optionA: "Sarje Himal",
        optionB: "Amodablem",
        optionC: "Pumori",
        optionD: "Makalu",
        correct: "c"
    },
    {
        question: "Which peak of Nepal is known as Shanti shikhar?",
        optionA: "Sarje Himal",
        optionB: "Amodablem",
        optionC: "Pumori",
        optionD: "Makalu",
        correct: "a"
    },
    {
        question: "Which peak of Nepal is known as Bhairav Takura?",
        optionA: "Sarje Himal",
        optionB: "Amodablem",
        optionC: "Pumori",
        optionD: "Jugal",
        correct: "d"
    },
    {
        question: "Which is the deepest valley of Nepal, which is also teh deepest valley in the world?",
        optionA: "Arun valley",
        optionB: "Waipio valley",
        optionC: "Nubra valley",
        optionD: "Hunza valley",
        correct: "a"
    },
    {
        question: "Which of the following state of India is not linked to Nepal?",
        optionA: "Uttar Pradesh",
        optionB: "Sikkim",
        optionC: "Uttrakhand",
        optionD: "Maharastra",
        correct: "d"
    },
    {
        question: "Which of the following state of India is linked to Nepal in the west?",
        optionA: "Uttar Pradesh",
        optionB: "West Bengal",
        optionC: "Uttrakhand",
        optionD: "Bihar",
        correct: "c"
    },
    {
        question: "Which state of India shares its most border length with Nepal?",
        optionA: "Uttar Pradesh",
        optionB: "West Bengal",
        optionC: "Uttrakhand",
        optionD: "Bihar",
        correct: "a"
    },
    {
        question: "Which treaty determined the Mechi river as eastern border and Mahakali as the western border of Nepal?",
        optionA: "Mahakali treaty",
        optionB: "Sugauli treaty",
        optionC: "Sino-Nepalese treaty",
        optionD: "None of the above",
        correct: "b"
    },
    {
        question: "What is the total length of international border line of Nepal?",
        optionA: "1236 km",
        optionB: "1690 km",
        optionC: "2926 km",
        optionD: "3028 km",
        correct: "c"
    },
    {
        question: "What is the length of international border line of Nepal touching India?",
        optionA: "1236 km",
        optionB: "1690 km",
        optionC: "2926 km",
        optionD: "3028 km",
        correct: "b"
    },
    {
        question: "What is the length of international border line of Nepal touching China?",
        optionA: "1236 km",
        optionB: "1690 km",
        optionC: "2926 km",
        optionD: "3028 km",
        correct: "a"
    },
    {
        question: "What is the nearest sea distance of Nepal?",
        optionA: "1125 km",
        optionB: "1126 km",
        optionC: "1127 km",
        optionD: "1128 km",
        correct: "c"
    },

    /* {
        question: "",
        optionA: "",
        optionB: "",
        optionC: "",
        optionD: "",
        correct: ""
    }, */



]
const Random = (data) => {
    const num = 5;
    const res = [];
    for (let i = 0; i < num;) {
        const random = Math.floor(Math.random() * data.length);
        if (res.indexOf(data[random]) !== -1) {
            continue;
        };
        res.push(data[random]);
        i++;
    };
    return res;
};
const gkRandom = Random(dataGk)

export { dataGk, gkRandom }